你是受雇抓猎物的吧  那就抓我吧
You were hired to do a job. So do it.
这不是你的准则吗
Isn't that your code?
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
你不是个有荣誉感的人吗
Aren't you a man of honor?
《曼达洛人》前情提要
翻译     哈里星球    累    RiverSide152
IG机器人  停火
IG Unit! Stand down.
校对     星星与野狗
你是公会成员吗
You are a Guild member?
我有个建议  我们平分报酬
I have a suggestion. We split the reward.
时间轴     累
我需要你的技能
I could use a crew member of your ability.
后期     累
我很荣幸  但我努力了一辈子
I am honored, but I have worked a lifetime
终于摆脱了奴役
to finally be free of servitude.
总监     星星与野狗
那我只能表示感谢了
Then all I can offer is my thanks.
彼此彼此
And I offer mine.
谢谢你给我的山谷带来和平
Thank you for bringing peace to my valley.
恩多之战以后  我基本上都在肃清余孽
I saw most of my action cleaning up after Endor.
主要是前帝国的军阀们
Mostly Ex-Imperial warlords.
小小的猎物  如此巨额的赏金
Such a large bounty for such a small package.
你知道他们会怎么做吗
Any idea what they're gonna do with it?
我没问
I didn't ask.
这违反公会规定
It's against the Guild Code.
星球大战
我的朋友  如果你接收到此讯息
My friend, if you are receiving this transmission,
那就是说你还活着
that means you are alive.
你可能没想到吧  可我也还活着呢
You might be surprised to hear this, but I am alive too.
我想我们就算扯平了吧
I guess we can call it even.
我们上次会面以后发生了很多事
A lot has happened since we last saw each other.
雇你的那个人还在这里
The man who hired you is still here,
而且他那批前帝国卫士的势力又壮大了
and his ranks of ex-Imperial guards have grown.
他们对我的城市施以暴政
They have imposed despotic rule over my city,
这影响到了公会的生计
which has impeded the livelihood of the Guild.
我们把他视为敌人
We consider him an enemy,
但却无法靠近他  把他干掉
but we cannot get close enough to take him out.
如果你愿意考虑接最后一个任务
If you would consider one last commission,
我会给你非常优厚的酬劳
I will very much make it worth your while.
到目前你都成功击退了他们派出的猎手
You have been successful so far in staving off their hunters,
但不拿到猎物他们是不会罢休的
but they will not stop until they have their prize.
我的条件是
So, here is my proposition.
回到尼瓦罗  用那孩子作为诱饵
Return to Nevarro. Bring the child as bait.
我来安排一次交接
I will arrange an exchange,
并派出可靠的公会成员提供保护
and provide loyal Guild members as protection.
一旦我们靠近雇主
Once we get near the client,
你把他杀掉  这样我们各取所需
you kill him, and we both get what we want.
如果你得手  孩子就归你了
If you succeed, you keep the child
我会在公会那边为你正名
and I will have your name cleared with the Guild,
毕竟正派的人不应该被迫亡命天涯
for a man of honor should not be forced to live in exile.
我满怀期待  等着你回来
I await your arrival with optimism.
曼达洛人
第一季  第七集
清算
掏钱吧  泥腿子们
Pay up, mudscuffers!
来吧  是我的钱  谢了
Come on. That's mine, thank you.
好的  谢谢
All right, thank you.
想找活干吗
Looking for some work?
看起来是个简单任务
It seems like a straightforward operation.
他们负责计划和武器  我当诱饵
They're providing the plan and firepower. I'm the snare.
-还有那孩子  -所以我才来找你
- With the kid? -That's why I'm coming to you.
我也不知道  人家说我应该猫起来
I don't know. I've been advised to lay low.
要是有人查了我的链码
If anybody runs my chain code,
我就得要把牢底坐穿了
I'll rot in a cell for the rest of my life.
你不是说你当过兵吗
I thought you were a veteran.
再来啊
Come back soon.
从那以后我干过很多行
I've been a lot of things since.
大部分都够我坐一辈子牢的
Most of them carry a life sentence.
只要我用新共和国注册的飞船
If I so much as book passage
订一个行程  我...
on a ship registered to the New Republic, I'm...
我有飞船  我可以带你过去再送你回来
I have a ship. I can bring you there and back
酬金丰厚
with a handsome reward.
你就可以衣食无忧了
You can live free of worry.
我已经衣食无忧了
I'm already free of worry,
而且我没有心情再去当兵打仗了
and I'm not in the mood to play soldier anymore.
尤其是和地方上的军阀战斗
Especially fighting some local warlord.
他不是地方上的军阀
He's not a local warlord.
他是帝国的
He's Imperial.
那我来
I'm in.
你的联络人要审核我吗
Does your contact need to vet me?
他不知道你会去
Doesn't know you're coming.
是吗  这有可能会有问题
Really? That could be a problem.
不会的
It won't.
就算有  也是他的问题
But if it is, that's his problem.
他自己待在那没事吧
He all right up there alone?
嗯
Yeah.
挑一件吧
Pick one.
你信任那个联络人吗
You trust the contact?
说不上
Not particularly.
上次我给公会做事时  我们俩有点争执
He and I had a run-in last time I was there on some Guild business.
那我们为什么还要去
So then why are we going?
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
在索尔根你都看见了
You saw what happened on Sorgan.
他们会不断派猎手来
They'll keep sending hunters.
那帝国人不死  孩子就不会安全
The kid will never be safe until the Imp is dead.
那把他带回去你就放心
And you're okay with bringing him back there?
不那么放心  所以我才带你去
Not really. That's why I'm bringing you.
我们得找个人看着点这小家伙
We need someone to watch that thing.
对
Yeah.
有什么你信得过的人吗
You got anyone you can trust?
慢点
Easy.
它没怎么长啊
It hasn't grown much.
我想它可能是链式塑模出来的
I think it might be a Strand-Cast.
我觉得它不是通过基因工程弄出来的
I don't think it was engineered.
我在基因工厂干过
I've worked in the gene farms.
这个看起来是进化来的  太难看了
This one looks evolved. Too ugly.
而这个呢
This one, on the other hand,
倒像是从诺拉的细胞培养穴里出来的
looks like she was farmed in the Cytocaves of Nora.
她是卡拉·杜恩  以前是震击士兵
This is Cara Dune. She was a shock trooper.
你是伞兵
You were a Dropper?
你当过兵吗
Did you serve?
恐怕是另外一头的
On the other side, I'm afraid.
但我很自豪地说  我已经偿还完我族的债务
But I'm proud to say that I paid out my clan's debt,
现在可以自己当家做主了
and now I serve no one but myself.
有人想喝点茶吗
Would anyone care for some tea?
请把枪放下  他不会伤害你们的
Please lower your blasters. He will not harm you.
那东西的设定任务是要杀死这孩子
That thing is programmed to kill the baby.
设定解除了
Not anymore.
你们捣毁了那里之后  它被丢下了
It was left behind in the wake of your destruction.
我发现它倒在原地
I found it laying where it fell.
生气全无
Devoid of all life.
我把遗骸捡了回来  并依据
I recovered the flotsam and staked it as my own
《新共和国宪章》  把它归我所有
in accordance with the Charter of the New Republic.
它的神经束几乎都没了
Little remained of its neural harness.
再造异常困难...
Reconstruction was quite difficult...
但也不是不可能
...but not impossible.
它必须从头学起
It had to learn everything from scratch.
这个可不是
This is something that
动动扳手就能教会的
cannot be taught with the twist of a spanner.
要有耐心  不断重复
It requires patience and repetition.
我日复一日地用耐心和鼓励
I spent day after day reinforcing its development
去巩固它的进步
with patience and affirmation.
随着经验的增加  它有了自己的个性
It developed a personality as its experiences grew.
它还是猎手吗
Is it still a hunter?
不  但它会保护
No. But it will protect.
喝茶吗
Tea?
我遇到了一些麻烦
I've run into some problems.
我想也是  不然你为什么回来
I figured as much. Why else would you return?
我想购买你的服务
I wanna hire your services.
我已经不提供服务了
I'm retired from service.
我可以付你很多钱  乌格瑙特人
I can pay you handsomely, Ugnaught.
我有名字  叫奎尔
I have a name. It is Kuiil.
我需要有人帮我保护这个小家伙  奎尔
I need someone to protect the little one, Kuiil.
这活不适合我
I'm not suited for such work.
我能重编IG-11的程序  让它拥有护理的功能
I can reprogram IG-11 for nursing and protocol.
不  我不希望那个机器人接近他
No. I don't want that droid anywhere near him.
你为什么这么不信任机器人
Why're you so distrustful of droids?
它想杀了他
It tried to kill him.
这是它的程序设定
It was programmed to do so.
机器人没有善恶之分
Droids are not good or bad.
它们只是反映了建造者的赋予它们的印记
They are neutral reflections of those who imprint them.
我见过别的情况
I've seen otherwise.
你信任我吗
Do you trust me?
根据我的判断  可以
From what I can tell, yes.
那就相信我的成果
Then you will trust my work.
IG-11会加入我
IG-11 will join me.
我们这么做不是为了报酬
And we do it not for payment,
而是为了保护那个孩子免遭帝国奴役
but to protect the child from Imperial slavery.
在粉碎旧的规则之前  没有人会得到自由
None will be free until the old ways are gone forever.
好吧
Okay.
布勒格兽也会加入我
And the blurrgs will join me as well.
布勒格兽
The blurrgs?
言止于此
I have spoken.
我赢定你了  曼达人
I got you, Mando.
敢加倍赌注吗
Care to double the bet?
不  不  不  住手
No! No, no! Stop!
我们是朋友  我们是朋友  卡拉是我朋友
We're friends, we're friends. Cara is my friend!
这样可不行
That is not okay!
很奇特
Very curious.
奇特  它差点杀了我
Curious? It almost killed me!
你和我讲过的那个泥角兽故事  现在听上去更合理了
The story you told me of the mudhorn now makes more sense.
-它是什么  -它是什么  我也不知道
- What is it? - What it is, I don't know.
但它能做到的事
But what it does, this...
我听说过传言
This I've heard rumors of.
什么  当你还在为帝国工作的时候
What? When you worked for the Empire?
当我以契约劳役被卖给帝国的时候
When I was sold to the Empire, in indentured servitude.
但是你却脱身了
Yet somehow, you walk free.
我通过手艺得到了自由
I bought my freedom through the skill of my hands
还有三个人类的终身劳役
and the labor of three of your human lifetimes.
不要质疑我是谁  抑或我为谁服务
Do not cast doubt upon that of what I am nor whom I shall serve.
这样吧  我现在正好用的上你的手艺
Tell you what. I could really use your craftwork right now.
你能给这个盒子装些软垫  让孩子睡得更舒服点吗
Can you pad this container so the child can sleep better?
我可以再做一个更好的
I shall fabricate a better one.
这样的话  也许这个伞兵就会知道
Then perhaps this Dropper can see how one can win their freedom
一个人如何凭手艺获得自由
with the skill of one's hands.
我们要去尼瓦罗吗
So, we're going to Nevarro?
-你去过吗  -没有
- Have you ever been? - No.
我们在那里失去了很多军队
We lost a lot of our forces there.
这个城市的位置很深
The city's dug in pretty deep.
进去的时候没有掩体
No cover when you drop in.
在战争结束前  都处于帝国管制下
It stayed in Empire control 'till the end of the war.
我们要去带走的那个军阀曾经是帝国的官员
The warlord we're taking out was an Imperial officer.
-什么职位  -不好说
- What station? - Hard to tell.
没有标章
No insignia anymore.
我抢走那个孩子的时候  摧毁了安全屋
I took out the safehouse when I snatched the kid.
在那之后  帝国的守卫更多了
More Imps have reinforced since.
水很深
There's something more going on.
也许吧  着陆之后再调查
Maybe. We'll find out more when we land.
我已经准备好了第二餐
I have prepared second meal.
你们想在这里用餐  还是在下面
Would you care to be served here or below?
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
无论如何都不能让这个机器人离开飞船
Under no circumstances does that thing leave the ship.
你对机器人还真有偏见  是吧
You got a real thing for droids, don't you?
我只是对那个机器人有偏见
I got a real thing for that droid.
那个乌格瑙特人说他已经重新接过线了
The Ugnaught said he rewired it.
那个机器人被设计成了一个杀戮工具
That droid was designed to kill things.
我才不管他重接了多少线
I don't care how much wiring he replaced.
这违反它的本性
It goes against its nature.
反正这活也不会花太久
Well, it shouldn't be a long job anyway.
消灭领头的帝国人  剩下的就会一哄而散
We take out the head Imp, the rest will run like rats.
很抱歉让你跑这么远和我见面  曼达人
Sorry for the remote rendezvous, Mando,
但你上次离开这里后  事态就变得复杂了起来
but things have gotten complicated since you were last here.
看来需要介绍一下
It appears that introductions are in order.
看来我们都带了保镖
It seems we've both provided a security detail.
我建议让那个震击士兵守船
I recommend the shock trooper guards the ship.
这片熔岩区里全是贾瓦人
These lava fields are lousy with Jawas.
她要跟我去
She's coming with me.
但那座城现在由前帝国管制
But the town is now run by ex-Empire.
如果一个反抗军伞兵和我们一起  他们会生气的
If a Rebel Dropper is with us, they'll all get their hackles up.
她必须同去
She's coming.
好吧
Fine.
至少挡住你的纹身
At least cover your tattoo.
没必要露出来炫耀
No need to flaunt it.
那个小家伙呢
Now, where is the little one?
原来这个小家伙才是你们你争我夺的原因
So, this little bogwing is what all the fuss was about.
真是个珍贵的小家伙
What a precious little creature.
我可以理解
I can see why you didn't
你们为什么不想动他一根毫毛
want to harm a hair on its wrinkled little head.
我很高兴可以一次性解决这件事
Well, I'm glad this matter will be put to rest once and for all.
尼瓦罗的太阳落得很快
The sun drops fast on Nevarro.
我们可以散会步  在河岸旁露营
We can walk for a spell, camp out at the riverbank,
天一亮就进城
then make our way into town at first light.
我猜那小家伙食肉
I guess the little bugger's a carnivore.
我从没见过像它这样的东西
Never seen anything like it.
他们准备高价赎回那个东西
They were ready to pay a king's ransom for that thing.
肯定是为了某种夸张的收藏
Must be for some kind of highfalutin menagerie.
我们再过一遍计划
Let's go over the plan again.
我们一起进入公房
We both enter the common house.
给客户看一眼诱饵
We show the client the bait.
和他一起用餐  然后你杀了他
We join him at the table. And you kill him.
描述一下他的护卫
Tell me about his reinforcements.
他们都是前帝国人
They're all ex-Empire.
给他们钱的人一死  他们就会一哄而散
As soon as they lose their paycheck, poof, they'll all scatter.
-如果他们没散呢  -会散的
- And what if they don't? - They will.
这还不够稳妥
That's not good enough.
就算假设他们中的一些人没有意识到
If, for argument's sake, a few of them don't realize
我才是他们最好的新雇主
that I'm their best path to alternative employment
而是选择了冲动行事
and they elect to react impulsively,
这三位优秀的公会猎手
then these three fine Guild Hunters,
还有这位身经百战的震击士兵
along with that battle-hardened shock trooper,
会解决掉那些反抗的人
will cut down anyone who bucks.
会有多少人
How many will there be?
不超过四个
No more than four.
他身边最多只有一个火力支援组
He travels with, at most, a Fire Team.
相信我
Trust me.
不会出差错
Nothing can go wrong.
不  放开她
No! Let go of her!
立刻放下她
Drop her now!
放下她
Drop her!
他受了很重的伤
He's hurt badly.
我没事  我没事  我没事
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
别动
Hold still.
他们把你伤得不浅
They got you good.
有多严重
How bad?
很糟糕
Bad.
毒素扩散得很快
The poison's spreading fast.
所以我要死了吗
So this... This is how it happens.
别这么多愁善感
Don't be so dramatic.
再来一个医疗包  还有医疗包吗
I need another medpac! Got any other medpacs?
还有吗
Anyone?
看来是没有了
I'm guessing that's a "No".
毒素还在蔓延
It's still spreading.
不管用
This isn't working.
把这家伙带出去
Get this thing outta here.
等等
Wait.
他要吃我
He's trying to eat me.
你觉得他们后悔了吗
You think they're having second thoughts?
可能吧
Could be.
我需要你的眼睛
I need your eyes.
我在观察
I'm watching.
就是这里了
I guess this is it.
我要告诉你们一件事
There's something you should know.
原本的计划是杀了你  带走那孩子
The plan was to kill you and take the kid.
但是昨晚发生了那样的事
But after what happened last night,
我真的做不到
I couldn't go through with it.
你现在可以开枪打死我
Go on. You can gun me down
也不会违反章程
here and now and it wouldn't violate the Code.
但是如果你这样做  这个孩子永远也不会安全
But if you do, this child will never be safe.
我们愿意试一试
We'll take our chances.
帝国的客户一心想获得这个孩子
The Imperial client is obsessed with obtaining this asset.
你们可以跑  但后果呢
You tried to run, but where did it get you?
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
你们听他说完
Perhaps you should let him speak.
我们都想干掉客户
Listen, we both need the client to be eliminated.
让我带孩子去见他  然后你们两个
Let me take the child to him and then you two...
-不  -我们杀了他  离开这里
- No. - Let's just kill him and get outta here.
他说得对
He's right.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
只要帝国人还活着  他就会派猎人追杀那个孩子
As long as the Imp lives, he'll send hunters after the child.
这是陷阱
It's a trap.
-带我去见他  -带你去
- Bring me. - Bring you?
跟他说你抓到我了
Tell him you captured me.
让我靠近他  我就干掉他
Get me close to him and I'll kill him.
这是个好主意  把你的爆能枪给我
That's a good idea. Give me your blaster.
这太疯狂了
This is insane.
-这是唯一的办法  -我和你一起去
- It's the only way. - Well, I'm coming with you.
不不不  他们会起疑的
No, no, no. That would make them suspicious.
我不管  我也要去
I don't care. I'm coming.
跟他们说她抓到我了
Tell them she caught me.
好吧  那她带上孩子
Fine. Then she can bring the child.
不  孩子得送回飞船
No. The kid goes back in the ship.
要是没有孩子  根本就不行啊
But without the child, none of this works!
我有个计划
I have a plan.
奎尔  带着孩子回刀锋之巅
Kuiil, ride back to the Razor Crest
然后封锁飞船
with the child and seal yourself in.
进入飞船以后  开启地面安全模式
When you're inside, engage ground security protocols.
这个星球的任何东西都无法进入
Nothing on this planet will breach those doors.
这是通讯器
Here's a comlink.
我会保护孩子的安全
I will keep the child safe.
别忘了盖住你的纹身
Don't forget to cover your stripes.
走吧
Let's go.
链码
Chain code?
我有个礼物送给老大
I have a gift for the boss.
链码
Chain code?
我愿意花二十买你的头盔
I'll give you 20 credits for the helmet.
没门  我要挂在墙上的
Not a chance. That's going on my wall.
挂在你的墙上
On your wall?
忍着吧
Go with it.
走吧
Go ahead.
你说只有四个护卫
You said four.
这里可不止四个暴风兵
There are more than four troopers.
四个守着客户  城里还有很多
Four guarding the client. Many more here in town.
曼达人突袭了安全屋以后  上头就加派了人手
Things got really heated once Mando crashed the safehouse.
把他的爆能枪给他
Slip him his blaster.
别急
Not yet.
到了
Here we are.
瞧  四个
You see? Four.
按照约定  我把他带来了
Look what I brought you. As promised.
多么精湛的手艺啊
What exquisite craftmanship.
先祖的工匠居然能锻造出
It is amazing how beautiful beskar can be
这么精致的曼达洛盔甲
when forged by its ancestral artisans.
我请你喝一杯吧
Can I offer you a libation
庆祝一下我们的合作圆满成功
to celebrate the closing of our shared narrative?
不胜感激
I would be obliged.
请坐
Please sit.
很遗憾  你们的人民遭受了如此的苦难
It is a shame that your people suffered so.
其实这一切都是可以避免的
Just as in this situation, it was all avoidable.
曼达洛人为什么抵制我们的扩张
Why did Mandalore resist our expansion?
帝国改进了触手所及的所有系统
The Empire improves every system it touches.
用任何标准看都很明显
Judge by any metric.
安全  繁荣  贸易  机会  和平
Safety, prosperity, trade, opportunity, peace.
比较一下帝国统治时和现在的状况吧
Compare Imperial rule to what is happening now.
看看外面
Look outside.
革命以后世界更和平吗
Is the world more peaceful since the revolution?
我只看到死亡和混乱
I see nothing but death and chaos.
我想看看孩子
I would like to see the baby.
它睡着了
It is asleep.
我们会很安静的
We all will be quiet.
打开婴儿车
Open the pram.
恕我无礼  我得接一下这个电话
Don't think me to be rude. I must take this call.
把爆能枪给我
Give me the blaster.
你只有一次机会
You get one shot.
不妙啊  你说只有四个暴风兵
This is bad. You said four.
不止四个  我能怎么办
Well, there are more. What can I tell you?
莫夫·吉迪恩
Yes, Moff Gideon?
他们把孩子带来了吗
Have they brought the child?
带来了  它正在睡觉
Yes, they have. Currently, it is sleeping.
再去看看吧
You may wanna check again.
四个暴风兵
Four stormtroopers?
糟了
This is bad.
奎尔  你回到飞船上了吗
Kuiil? Are you back to the ship yet?
在吗  收到了吗
Are you there? Do you copy?
嗯
Yes!
-你回到飞船上了吗  -还没有
- Are you back to the ship yet? - Not yet.
回到飞船以后赶紧走  把孩子带走
Get back to the ship and bail. Get the kid out of here.
我们被敌人压制了
We're pinned down!
你们有我想要的东西
You have something I want.
这家伙是谁
Who's this guy?
你们可能以为
You may think you have
你们很了解自己拥有的东西
some idea of what you are in possession of,
但你们不了解
but you do not.
奎尔  你回到飞船了吗  我们被包围了
Kuiil, are you back to the ship yet? They're onto us!
奎尔  快回话
Kuiil, come in!
再过一会儿  它就是我的了
In a few moments, it will be mine.
奎尔  收到了吗
Kuiil! Do you copy?
奎尔
Kuiil!
它对我来说比你想象中重要得多
It means more to me than you will ever know.
奎尔  在吗
Kuiil! Are you there?
回复  奎尔
Come in, Kuiil.
奎尔  快回复
Kuiil, come in.
奎尔  你在吗
Kuiil? Are you there?
收到了吗
Do you copy?
奎尔
Kuiil?
Kuiil!